Good truth, to understand what God does in our lives and be able to
Understand many things in our hearts, right?Many times we believe that
We are fine, this time we have been talking about many situations, capable that has to do with
People and capable are calm, capable we believe we are doing things well, but
Many times we forget that God always has a purpose, right?And even though
There may be a need or not, many times God always sees the intention of
our hearts and he is always there to see what what we have to do
And sometimes we are calm, right?We are very apparently, but God wants something else
From us, God wants something different, we will share something that many times capable
We have heard it, many times we have shared, capable have heard this word, but it has to
See with the intention of our hearts and how God also sees those intentions.I first
I'm going to talk to you something descriptive, let's imagine or imagine that we were at that time
Where is the Lord Jesus, we could not terra
Things and we can leave the biblical text.And that we have an interview of a person who had
had an encounter with the Lord, that God had done something in his life and the story a little
Testimony of how it rose is transformed.And what happens?A character is known, it is a
Bible character, which we have often heard.Bartimaeo called me, the son of
Timéo, but scam and my mother generated blind, I had never seen the light, I didn't know what a
Color, he never met a face, he didn't know what a smile was.My world was a poor world,
Not only because I didn't have his eyes, but either after wealth, a family that
Soon he said to me because my own still accused them, a city that expelled me because my
presence was the mark of weakness, this was my life, next to the road, in the Anteua,
The old rap jericop, that of the walls lying down, the rebuilt, at the price of blood, blessed and
Damn Jericop.Damn for me, from my crib, although my crib gave me, to think that the blind man was
I, but there were many who accused me, who mistreated me, that marginalized me, that discarded me,
It was they who saw the human being that I am, did not know about my dreams, without images,
of my desire, without answers, colds of the world, and I although blind, I saw, I saw the pride of
The mediacrés, the legalism that it expels, the painful disease of those who believe they are healthy because
Come, do not see their own pocado, which is the worst illness, blind and poor, but not so blind and poor
Like some rich vidan, blind does not mean deaf, and listened to the passerships of the thousand
caravans that passed from the length, enriched my poor world with the sounds and voices with the
Amedias stories that came to me with the comments when I passed, and History Companies began to
I answer again and again, one man, one Jesus, and listened to many things about the things there were
Fact, some said, the Hitico had walked in Jerusalem, near Siloé's tobill,
that the demons were at their voice and their presence, a girl had been resurrected and cited,
I arrive, you listened to those stories and as I wanted to believe them, I wanted to know that it was true and that if
He was close to mine could have an opportunity, occasionally when some with a little more
Desimpatía stopped close to me took to ask and so I learned that it was believed that
He was a descendant of King David, who had been baptized by Juan and that at that time he had
manifested the abo of God, the rumors announced that he was a prophet of the ancients, in the style of
Managers, or at the same day he turned to Earth, once a follower of John, the
baptizer prophet that had been killed by Hereores, he did treated me well, even me
He gave the layer he had, because he said that this was what John taught and that Jesus was the one who
Juan had announced, told me that Juan when he was in jail had sent him and others from
His followers, to meet Jesus to ask whether he was the bedside table or had to wait
To others, those things that I listened to, that I moved in the comments of the travelers and
That they were my own mushroom, the deepest of my claims, the most dream of my dreams, thus
That was the true told me and if it were true I came to the conclusion, it will be the Messiah and if
It is the Messiah will sooner or later come to Jerusalem and will have to go through Jericho and I will have the
opportunity to ask you like others to look at me and effectively the day arrived, I heard
The rumors, I prepared my soul, was the opportunity of my life and I was not going to lose, so when I knew
That I was close, I began to call it, to call it from what I wanted to believe, Jesus, son of David,
It wasn't the towal that wanted to shut me up, but how I was silent I had to sound my voice more
that again, if something true there were in Jesus in what I had heard of him, I had to hear me,
I had to hear, that I was blind, the poor, the hurt, the marginalized, that nobody understood, it was
That, the Jesus I imagined and my blind imagination, and me or me, and made me approach,
It is altered like a spring, there flew the layer that the disciple Juan guided by
The voices ran their encounter in the last act of my seguera and then a question arose
Unusual, a question that touched my heart over and over again, I can put the disciple of
The message, and I try to contextualize a question, we could say that I can do for
You, but Lord Jesus told this blind Bartimaeus, what do you want me to do for you?
What are you Sante?We are going to say to the book of Lucas, Lucas, and we will be able, more or less see, the
text, right?To be able to contextualize a little to what happened and how it was.
Lord Jesus with Bartimaeus, Luke, Chapter 18, verse 35, did he answer that Jesus approaching us
Jericho?A blind man was sitting next to the road begging, and to go to the crowd that passed,
He asked that it was that, and they told him that Jesus, Nazarene, then voices saying,
Jesus, son of David, had mercy on me, and those who went, in front of him so that
I shut up, but he who goes to much more, son of David Ten my sericord of me, than his
Then stopping, he ordered him to bring him to his presence, and when he arrived he asked him,
Saying, what do you want me to do you there just?How interesting, right?That question,
What do you want me to do?What do you want me to do for you?What do you want me to do for you?
We could say it, right?That encounter that the Lord had with Bartimaeus.Now, look at a
Curious thing, right?We were contextualizing, and obviously he was there and he was a beggar,
But he was blind, right?And the question would be, why did the Lord Jesus ask him,
What do you want me to do for you?It was not obvious that he was blind and that what he needed capable
It was humanly to see.He will have thought about his heart, right?They will really be enesid,
Are you not realizing that I can't see and that I need this?Why is it that
The Lord Jesus asked him that question?What do you want me to do for you?What do you want me to do for you?TRUE?
because?Now it's very interesting, right?This question has an intention.
Simple, sir, go beyond what we see, beyond what we believe,
And we could seek many explanations that Jesus wanted to prove his faith.Those wanted to see
Truly what was the intention of his heart.How interesting, right?And they know, many
times throughout our life we are also happening some situations.Many
very difficult situations, in which we have tried to find an answer and we have not
found.We have gone to other places we have even been able to look for God too, but
We have found answers.But let's imagine that at a given time in all that time,
We have an encounter with Jesus and that we would have, I don't know physically or
Not capable, but that we listen to that voice that God tells us and what calls us, right?
And that I would ask us what you want me to do for you, what do you want me to do for you.AND
What happened you could arise that.This is a man who was happening many situations.We set
A little the historical context, some data that say them are valid and you look for
In the historical part, this is a contemporary narrative and many of the data are void,
Able that the form is a bit different, but this man is.This man had been
marginalized because he was a person who could not be a person who could be part of the
society because I had an inability and many times we listen to that, but I want us to
Let's go a little more to be able to see the intention of the question, right?And why many times
The yes, we don't see, right?And many times he wants to see our intention of the
Thing we are living.So, for you or is facing that situation, right?
And at that moment the abso so fast, I need, I obviously, I can't see, this is my need.
But, despite that, the Lord tells him, what do you want me to do to you?
It's very interesting, right?Because the Lord always see other things that we do not see
And it is also disappearing what are the intentions of our heart and truly what are the
Things that we are yearning and if those things are well or are not right, right?
What do you want me to do?We are going to the book of Mateo, Chapter 7, Mateo, Chapter 7, verse 7,
And there we have some answers.What does not say the Lord?Order and you will be given, search and find,
call and open, verse 8, why everyone who asks receives and the one who seeks and who
Call will open, right?The Lord was telling us, he was teaching that one has to ask
To the father, one has to know that we will find an answer.Here was this blind, right?
And he was seeing a need that he had practically.Then he was asking and he
I was calling.Then the Lord Jesus, at that time of the entire crowd that was happening,
He stopped, he did what he had to do, he took it into account, although there were people who
that he had discarded, he took into account this man that he was asking for something, not just that,
but sent him to call.And when he sent him to call, he was in front of him, that is, he took a
time to be with him.It is a long time something of our life, the Lord murdered sisters,
That took time to be with us.He is not heard, he takes all the
Needs that we are happening, but they also know the intention of our heart.
See what intention is.And Bartimae will have been re -questioned again, and is not seeing
What you are still.Obviously that is what I need.As I told them, let's imagine that
Lord was there, right?And he asks you, or I don't know if we are happening any need,
I don't know if you have a need today.Such a difficult situation that many times capable, nobody
He knows, that has to do with a personal aspect, which has to do with a family aspect, that
It has to see capable with a loved one.It is much time to have to do with work.Much time
It has to do with your body, because there is something that is failing, you already feel tired,
Or he feels tired of always a disease, a situation with his health.Layers a
something.And at that time in all that situation, well I find the Lord Jesus.And the Lord
He tells us and tells you, tells me, what do you want me to do for you?And what is many
Sometimes we have heard, but I already asked the Lord.I have long
I have said that Lord does this in my life, that God transforms this, that he worked with my family,
That this situation turns at work and nothing happens and I don't see any response.
And we could have many explanations and I am going to give some, why don't it happen?Come on
To the book of Santiago, Chapter 4. Santiago, Chapter 4, Verse 2 First.Discounted
The 3. Thank you, Malico.He says, do you elbow and don't have?Matá and Ardeis de Envidia and you can't
Reach, fight and fight, but you don't have what you want because you don't ask.And here comes
The key verse, right?I am important that we ask, they have at the youth meeting
That we said virtual, they speak a little of this, right?Sometimes you have to hort specifically
of what we are happening.But here Santiago, which is his very particular book that does not speak
Characteristic of adequate Christian behavior, how do you not have to handle a Christian?God
He speaks to us through Santiago and says, you ask and do not receive, because you ask badly to spend on
Your delites.And they know, many times it has to do with that.We are selfish and many
Sometimes we ask for our needs that is wrong, it's wrong, right?But many
times goes beyond that.We ask because we want something that we believe has to be
So.We ask for pride, we ask for envy, or many times we ask because we want that
It's right.And capable spend a lot of time and we spend many situations and we don't see an answer.And the
Santiago's book tells us that, Lord Belé is the intention of our heart.If we are
asking for something because we have a personal well -being, we want because that will help us
We feel good and capable is a bit selfish on our part.Or capable we ask because this
It will not allow feelings better and believe that we can achieve things that other people cannot reach.
But many times God sees the intention.The secret many times the answer of what God
It is because it sees the intention of our heart.Why do we ask?What do we ask for?TRUE?So that
We ask?And therefore we what do we aspire when we ask the Lord something?
We aspire to our personal benefit.What's not bad, right?Because it would be good.Because one
You want to feel good, capable of you aspire to have a house, aspire to have a vehicle, aspire to have
Good profession, aspire to have a good family, aspire to have a good relationship with their parents,
With their children and that is good, but that is his things.But capable of Jamal side, something that
It is very important that it has to do with those aspirations in which God wants to do something
In our life.Many times God sees without us ask for things to see the
God's blessing in our life.Because God wants to bless our life.Not for the
Things that we want important, but for the things that God wants to do with us.
And that through that we can share our families, we can share our
loved ones, we can share the people we call, we can share with our partners
of work, we can share with our neighbors.The Lord see that right?Go, practically
What is my aspiration?Personal look, my greed, my codice, my pride, I aspire because I want
May God do that complete work in my life.They know, today we are living special times,
TRUE?We are in a time of grace and here we are privileged because we have the freedom of
To be able to share the word of the Lord and be able to have freedom, we are.And we are seeing that in
Some places are not like that, in some places they cannot share the Word of God.It has to
Being hidden, I shared with Mary that some places are prohibited to be a Christian,
You can't pray, or if you see it out, we still have certain freedoms yet.
And all that has to do with what I did the Word of God, right?The things that will happen in
The last time, these eschatological situations that we can manipulate, but we are seeing,
Natural disasters, wars, all these situations right?A technology that reaches
Maximum, as to go, we saw yesterday showed me a small video in which I think a singer
He spoke with the AI Right?And I asked him if he existed, what happened after death,
What happened to the resurrection?And the AI answers, well, there a, but recognize
of Jesus, who was the Son of God, and there he spoke of some situations that if the antichrist was,
He wasn't, and said that if he had arrived, because we beat, right?It was the antichrist,
A computer will be AI, it will be people, that's it, and all those things that can
Press in our life.And we live like this, in which we are accessing a lot of information,
What did not have it before?I remember when I was a boy if you did not have a newspaper or not
I would see the TV and capable had nothing else, I couldn't enter a computer and be able to do
Everything we do, and we are contemporaries, all nor the merdo?TRUE?TRUE?Did you have or that?
There was no more, today is another time that can acquire anything and can have that freedom.
But notice how interesting, right?Know that God wants to bless our life and know
that we are also part of the people of God, and as part of the people of God God also have
A purpose with us, and God also wants to do something in our life, God wants
That we do something too, something in our life.Last Sunday we talked a little about this,
truth, that the Lord is like that potter who is molding and that many times we pass
Things, we live, we have experience, we live a lot of situations, but that does not do
Ébalidos that this training process will always be, although we have experience,
Although it is more capo in the things we do, because God always perfects us.
The apostle Paul does not say that we can reach the fullness of Christ, right?
And then the Lord, how that good potter is not going to perfect.Now the Lord sees the intention.
I want to approach, right?To the Lord, or I ask the Lord something, and many times we
We ask the Lord something, why are we whims?Why do we want something?And that a
Lord goes, for his love and for his mercy, but there is a point where the situation remains
As in this puffy, right?Lord, nothing moves, and we are there asking, crying out,
asking, crying out, and Lord, does nothing, because he is seeing our intention.The Lord
What he had to do at that moment with Bartimae was done, he heard it, he saw it, called it,
He had a relationship with him and not just that, he said, what do you want me to do for you?
You need his need, but there was an obvious need, right?But he is not seeing that I continue,
The same as the Lord asked him, because he always sees, as I said, beyond, there is an intention
With that question, to see, who really?And there would have happened many things,
Able Bartimaeus, will go up, and not jado, he says, ah, this is not a prophet!How are you not realizing
that I am blind and will go up, or that another has passed, I would have said, no, I, the truth, I want
That you give me a house, I want me to give me money, capable, it will have said, this is humiliated, that capable,
Well, you can do anything, but there was an intention and God many times in our life, you see intention.
He wants to fulfill a purpose with us, he sees our heart, he wants our life
be it changes and that we can grow too.And he wants to bless us, he wants to bless us
Really, but Mr. V, the intentions of the heart, as the book of Vios says, we will say,
Ah, Hebrews, chapter 4, verse 12, we have often heard it, because the word
of God is alive and effective and cutter than all the edges, and penetrates until it leaves
of the soul and the spirit, the coyontures and the marrows, since the phrase is key and
discerns the thoughts and intentions of the heart, the Word of God, which is the presentation
of God himself, discerns the thoughts, God discerns our thoughts and he sees more
Even, not only our mind, but the deepest, because what comes out of your mouth is
The one in his heart and the Lord says, discerns the intentions of the heart.
How wonderful God God, right?And he sees, and many times things are left like this because
God is waiting for something else from us, why are we asking?What
Are you looking for?TRUE?You are looking for me, you want, I do that complete work with you,
Or you are only looking for your needs, I always go to our needs.
They know when a child is growing, it goes through several stages, there is a stage that has to do with
what is smaller or early childhood, which the child obviously learning, but
There comes a time between the two bathrooms that has to identify certain things.The baby first
The six months tells Guu, Joa, Ja, and then it is easier to say the pa than the ma, then
For there he says more dad, despite how Mom says, but after the year, year and a half he has
What to say it behind, if a child to the two bathrooms, I tell me dad and mom, dad and not
Something else is happening, because it has to have a little more language, it has to
Understand at least 30 words and say short phrases.So if that child is three years old
Says dad and mom, dad and mom, dad and mom, and says nothing else, there is a problem.So
Many times the child is being taught and the child capable does so, and we know that it is a
chair, but time has passed and has to say chair, but we who do and
We give the chair.Then the boy gets used not to say chair, because I'm going to say chair if I
And he points to me, but if a moment appears and that child tells me I don't give it to me and I tell him
What do you want, what's the name of that, and he will insist and insist that he will go to a moment as not
We give him, he is going to say chair.Ah, you're the chair, yes, then I come and give it to him.Many
I am in such a deal with us.We passed throughout life, we
We get used, truth, I will always be there, he will bless us, but a point comes in our
Life that we have to define something and that we have to do.I can't say no, we have
what to say and many times they go years and years we are, we have to talk, we have to decide,
We have to do what we have to do, because what corresponds to us.How interesting,
TRUE?And this is capable that is simple, not man, it is something practical, but you say like this and God
Know our life and know our heart.Let us return to Lucas's book again, verse 41.
So that context is, right?I am not going to talk much about the miracle or what I said,
No, I'm going to talk more about the question.So, the Lord tells him, what do you want me to do to you?And he
He said, sir, that he receives his eyes.He didn't have you, right?There he says, coma, that he receives his eyes,
It was an affirmative, it was that and my need, that I receive the view.We go to 42, which usually
He said, receives, God does the miracle, your faith has saved you.So, how will a plus be
Lord, right?Your faith has saved you.No, it is not only that it received it, but you
Faith has saved you.That is, here something happened in your life, it will no longer be Bartimaeus, it is not
Just because I look.The Lord could have said it, the ready, you are already healthy,
Ready, no!But he says, your faith has saved you.There is something else.He had an encounter with the teacher.
He saw the intention of his heart.He believed and knew that he could be a miracle because it wasn't a
Prophet more, but was the Son of God.And that's why he arranged and said it, right?He doesn't
He had, he did not say, well, if you are the Messiah, then, to do something, or I heard that this is the prophet,
No, he doesn't doubt.We will hear a little to the contextualization that I told him at the beginning.
Stroke and say, and I hate myself and made me approach.I jump like a spring, there flew the layer that
He had given the disciple of Juan, guided by the voices, ran his encounter.In the last act
I would still.And then, this unusual question, the same one we hear.What do you want me to do for
you?And here this particular departure, right?He says, for a moment, I hesitated.¿Acaso, si es el mesías,
You shouldn't know my need?Isn't it evident that I am blind?And what what else
It is seeing, why do you have to ask me what is obvious?But I did not hesitate the answer.Teacher
I see, I said.Remarking it obvious.You already know the result, because now I see.But I came back
Again and again the unusual question and I realized that all the secret was locked in it
of human freedom.Jesus did not think about me, he made me express my own desire, my own
I wish in him.It made me do what I always wanted to do.When the others had sent me to
Cachar, he made me talk.When the others had me to the side, he put me in the center,
making me, making me say my own feeling.When the other despised me, they did not take the
I count on my appreciation and wanted to listen to me.When for others it was simply one more to side
From the road to him I was the human being who could say what his own dignity means.
He didn't think about me, I don't speak for me, he didn't decide for me.It gave me room for my own desire,
My own voice, my own decision.The blind from the side of the road thinks, speaks, decides what
He wants in front of David's son.I was the authority, he put at my service.What do you want me to do for
you?And I fulfilled me, with my request, but he did not do it without me, he did it with my faith.Saved me,
He saved me from dignity, from my own, of mockery, of poverty that disqualifies the heartbreak that
excludes.That silly question, so he says, the author was the deepest of all.The one that
He truly showed why the messiah is truly.Because before taking his eyes, I had
Returned the word, I had returned my dignity, I had become human again.How interesting,
Truth, here the author talks about the pain situation, as a human being, which had
past.But many times throughout our life, we are like this, right?And we are
Hoping that lady do something in our life.And we have that encounter, which appears a
our lord.And he tells us, what do you want me to do for you?And the question would be
What would we say, right?And that obvious things go, that you go out you have a disease and you are
Taking medication, and you are taking many things, or you are doing studies, and you see that
There is not an answer, and what happens?It is a necessity.Or capable has to do with a personal situation
In your life, in your heart, something that you cannot handle, capable of your character, your way of being,
able to invent in your heart, capable of something that you cannot leave something you see, something that
You take, something that you make you improper, and you have tried in a lot of way.
And you have to deal with that every day, try and cannot leave.I remember that when we were
We, when I was, God was working in my life, right?And I was like
compas a whole church that was called in your Cumán, municipal neighborhood, and there was a person who
He wanted to do things well from the previous one, he wanted to serve the Lord, but he had a problem,
The problem was him, he is Ibarrillo, he smoked, and he knew of God, he read the word,
He tried, and I remember this process, we talked, I speak a lot of time with him,
He said, well yes, yes, I'm fine, and when I saw it, I saw it, he does, the
smell feels, so, so, so.
The atmosphere was a bit complicated, because everything really was, and it was a fight that he
I had, and I remember this word many times, because we talked to him a little about this,
that God can make us free, of any situation, but the least is the Trival, now I do
That, the Lord does that for what purpose, so that the elora of God is revealed,
so that God wants to sell your life, or for you to tell you, well, I did it, I did it,
I do not have to be careful, I often share three things that destroy the human being,
And even more to the people who serve the Lord too, it is power, sex and money,
They are things that destroy, what would be able to have a church, a church, a thousand, very filled,
impressive, if my heart there is vanity, if my heart just want you to be talking about me
And I go out, and he is a person who has control of all things, and I think it's fine, I don't
It would help, because the vibula says that we will have to appear before God,
And each one will appear before the Lord, both just and unfair,
The Lord is seen that we can fulfill his purpose, to be able to do his perfect will,
But it also has to do with the intention in our hearts,
We saw some aspects, because this is very long, but some aspects to realize,
Many times that sir is not being called, and what happened this morning is telling us what
You want me to do for you, and the question is what are we going to do?
It is if we have really understood, right?We might think like bartimaeus, well,
I have this problem with this situation, right?Play problem, money problem,
Alcohol problem, sex problem, problem with my mind, what is me?It is obvious capable,
But Lord asks us what do you want me to do for you?Because he sees our hearts,
He sees the deepest, and he wants to bless our life, and that we, if we are blessing to
other people, and that we can also convey what God has done our lives to
Share or with those people who do not know, or for those people who knew and departed,
Or for those who believe they have the absolute truth of things and do not know God,
And God is calling us, how good we can be able to stop a little, right?
And able to rethink many things, say, the Lord that you want you to do, right?
Because many times we condition God to our plans, I remember committing that
He left with the Lord, and it's an example, right?She said, like that, I want you to do this,
I want you to do the other, I want you to transform, I want you to, and many times we are
Thus, I am Lord, I want you to do this, to transform, to do this, but many times the
Question would be, Lord, what do you want us to do?Or there is something in me that you need
Be changed, help me, because sometimes we are denied, right?I also put on, right?
Because sometimes we want we have no problem, and we have many problems.
When there is a situation with people, when there is a different treatment, when there is a circusance
Different, when it clashes with unique, another, when there are complications at home, is it more?
Whether it costs more?We can't say, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, it's not all right, does it cost more?
And that is where we must deepen, say sir, help me, right?And there we
Seeing ourselves and seeing our hearts, how is it?And this we saw talking
Little of that, some Sundays behind, right?Regarding that we have to discern when there is a
Spirit of rebellion, a spirit practically in which I do what I want as me, it seems
that is that self -sufficiency, that it is not pending anything, and anyone who does not come
of God, and that God is love, and the love of God is that he smells of ours, our life is the one who
It transforms into our heart, and the love of God is what allows us to see things that others, others
We do not see, we cannot love humanly, because God is love.If you pomecí, sir,
Help us through your love to be able to achieve that love, but humanly as humans we cannot,
Through the love of God, we can, because God is love.So brother or friends who don't
Come in Interneces and the Lord finds us today this morning and he would tell us this,
What do you want me to do, what do you want me to do for you, let us give it.